Guide to the Alice M. Rose Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League collection, 1900-1943
Department of Special Collections
Alice M. Rose Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League collection,
1900-1943
Special Collections M0101
Rose, Alice M.
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Alice M. Rose, 1947.
Biography
Alice Rose attended Stanford University and received her A.B. in 1928, A.M. in 1929 and Ph.D. in 1942 all in the field of history. She taught history at Roseville Union High School in Roseville, California.
Scope and Content
Correspondence and reports of personal interviews relating to the origins of the Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League founded in 1907, principally in California. Materials prior to the late 1930's are copied from other collections in Stanford University Libraries, and the remainder are correspondence and interviews resulting from Miss Rose's research. Principal names mentioned include Thomas R. Bard, John R. Haynes, Meyer Lissner, George C. Pardee, Arthur J. Pillsbury, Chester H. Rowell, and Lincoln Steffens.
Access Terms
Avery, Russ.; Bard, Richard.; Bard, Thomas Robert, 1841-1915.; Baumgartner, J. P.; Dam, Francis H.; Fletcher, Ed.; Hathorn, Ralph.; Haynes, John Randolph, 1853-1937.; Hichborn, Franklin, b.1869.; Lissner, Meyer, 1871-1930.; Luce, Edgar A. b.1881.; Madsen, Martin C.; Marx, Guido H., 1871-1949.; Mumford, Anne.; Needham, James Carson, 1864-1942.; Pardee, George Cooper, b.1857.; Pillsbury, Arthur Judson.; Powers, Harold T.; Rowell, Chester Harvey, 1867-1948.; Spreckels, Rudolph, 1872-; Stanton, Philip A.; Steffens, Lincoln, 1866-1936.; Stimson, Marshall.; Tarbell, Ida.; Wallace, Albert J.; Wood, Perry.; Young, C. C. (Clement Calhoun), 1869-1947.; Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League.; Political parties--United States.; Women.
Container List
- Bard, Thomas R., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bard, Thomas R., 1906-1914 (Box 1, Folder 2-10)
- Bard, Thomas R. Prospectus on Good Government sent by Meyer Lissner (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Dam, Francis H., 1906, 1907, and 1939 Apr.-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Dickson, Edward A., 1906 Aug. - 1907 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Green, R.L.: Index and explanation (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Green, R.L.: correspondence, 1904-1915 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Green, R.L.: Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Green, R.L.: Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Green, R.L.: Progressive Party, national (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Green, R.L.: Progressive Party, California (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Green, R.L.: San Francisco Grant Prosecution (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Hathorn, Ralph (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Haynes, John R. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Marx, Guido H. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Pardee, George C., 1937 Dec. - 1938 Mar.; [1939 Mar.] (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Pillsbury, Arthur Judson: excerpts from diary (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Rowell, Chester H.: index (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Rowell, Chester H., 1906-1910 (Box 1, Folder 27-31)
- Rowell, Chester H., 1911-1914 (Box 2, Folder 32-37)
- Rowell, Chester H.: Charles E. Hughes' California trip (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Rowell, Chester H., 1918-1919 (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
- Rowell, Chester H., 1930 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Rowell, Chester H.: Miscellaneous documents (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Rowell, Chester H.: Letters to Dr. Chester Rowell (uncle), 1901-1911 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Rowell, Chester H.: correspondence on Rowell materials: proposed articles or books, 1911-1914, 1917, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Rowell, Chester H.: Lissner statement to Tarbell, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Rowell, Chester H.: Guido H. Marx correspodence (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Rowell, Chester H.: R.L. Green statement to Tarbell, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Rowell, Chester H.: Rowell statement to Tarbell, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Rowell, Chester H.: Tarbell notes on Rowell interview (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Steffens, Lincoln: letters (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Wallace, A.J.: biography (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Wood, John Perry: Index (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Wood, John Perry: correspondence (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Wood, John Perry: correspondence on Citizen's Alliance (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Wood, John Perry: Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Wood, John Perry: personal campaign for Superior Judge, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: 1934-1943: correspondence between Alice Rose and League leaders, Index (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: A-B (Box 3, Folder 58-59)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Bard, Richard (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: C-D (Box 3, Folder 61-62)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Dickson, E.A. (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: E-F (Box 3, Folder 64-65)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Fletcher, Ed (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: G-H (Box 3, Folder 67-68)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Hichborn, Franklin (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: J-L (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Libraries (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Luce, E.A. (Box 3, Folder 72)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: M (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Martin, Irving (Box 3, Folder 74)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Mumford, Anne (Box 3, Folder 75)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: N (Box 3, Folder 76)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Newspapers (Box 3, Folder 77)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: O-P (Box 3, Folder 78-79)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Powers, Harold T. (Box 3, Folder 80)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: R-T (Box 3, Folder 81-83)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: Thelen, Max (Box 3, Folder 84)
- Lincoln-Roosevelt League: W-Z (Box 3, Folder 85-86)
- Status of California Democracy, 1900-1908 (Box 3, Folder 87)
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 88)
- Personal interviews: reports / by Alice Rose (Box 3, Folder 89)
- Origin of the Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League by Alice Rose. Paper fpr Political Science 102, 1934 June 1 (Box 3, Folder 90)